A Guide to the J. C. Curtis and Co. Records, 1907-1929
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
J. C. Curtis and Co. Records, 1907-1929
The Library of Virginia
44877
2.9 cubic feet (7 boxes and 1 oversize folder)
J. C. Curtis and Co. (Warwick County, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jeff Burgwinkle and Minda Estrada, Suffolk, Virginia, 4 September 2009.
Biographical Information
James C. Curtis (1875-1946) was a general contractor and builder in the town of Denbigh in Warwick County, Virginia (now Newport News). He married Hortense Valette Bass (1881-1941) and with her had six children.
Scope and Content
Records, 1907-1929, of J. C. Curtis and Co., a general contractor in Denbigh, Warwick County (present-day Newport News), Virginia, chiefly include correspondence, bids, estimates, and invoices. Major projects referenced include work on the Naval Mine Depot in Yorktown, a men's dormitory at the College of William and Mary, the State Normal and Industrial Schools for Women in Fredericksburg and Radford, and a residence for a Mrs. A. W. Clark, at 66th Street and Huntington Avenue in Newport News.
Arrangement
Original order has been maintained as closely as possible. The collection arrived in eight letter file boxes and one batch of loose papers. Each letter file box was given an arbitrary label (A, B, C, etc.) and the contents transferred to acid-free folders and boxes. The loose papers were also kept together and transferred to archival-quality housing.
Contents List
- J. C. Curtis and Co. Records, 1907-1929., Extent: 7 boxes and 1 oversize folder. (Box 1-7)
  - Letter File Box A, 1908-1910. (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
    Projects referenced include: Manassas, Va., high school building (1908-1909); State Normal and Industrial School for Women at Radford, Va. (1908-1910).
  - Letter File Box B, 1907-1909. (Box 1, Folder 8-12)
    Projects referenced include: Lee School, Alexandria, Va. (1908); Danville School, Danville, Va. (1909); Highland Park School, Richmond, Va. (1909); State Normal and Industrial School for Women at Harrisonburg, Va. (1908); Northside Baptist Church, Richmond (1907); grammar school in Petersburg, Va. (1908); Roanoke County Courthouse, Salem, Va. (1908); female college dormitory, Williamsburg, Va. (1907).
  - Letter File Box C, 1909-1911, 1914-1916. (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
    Projects referenced include: State Normal and Industrial School for Women at Fredericksburg, Va. (1909-1911); Ginter Park, Maury, Franklin, and Bainbridge Schools, Richmond (1914-1915); State Normal and Industrial School for Women at Radford (1916); G. P. Byrum apartment house, Newport News, Va. (1915); addition to high school building, South Boston, Va. (1915); Newport News Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Company (1916); State School for Colored Deaf and Blind Children, Newport News (1916); C & O Railway hospital, Clifton Forge, Va. (1915); St. Paul's Episcopal Church parish house, Newport News (1916); C & O Railway office building, Newport News (1916); St. Vincent's Roman Catholic Church, Newport News (1916); John B. Kimberly garage, Newport News (1916); office and apartment building, Drs. Jones and Coleman (1916); Jackson Hall, Virginia Military Institute, Lexington (1916).
  - Letter File Box D, 1910-1912. (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    Project: State Normal and Industrial School, Fredericksburg.
  - Letter File Box E, 1928-1929. (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
    Project: Mrs. A. W. Clark residence, Newport News (1928-1929).
  - Letter File Box F, 1923-1924. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Project: Men's dormitory, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg.
  - Letter File Box G, 1916-1918. (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
    Project: G. B. James apartment house, Newport News.
  - Letter File Box H, 1922-1923. (Box 5, Folder 1-11)
    Project: Power house and dispensary, Naval Mine Depot, Yorktown, Va.
  - Loose papers, 1907-1929. (Box 6-7)
    Projects referenced include: School building in Waverly, Va. (1908); Appomatox Agricultural High School (1908); State Normal and Industrial School for Women at Fredericksburg (1911); State Normal and Industrial School for Women at Radford (1912); Dispensary in barracks, Naval Mine Depot, Yorktown (1922); men's dormitory, College of William & Mary (1923). Also includes A. M. Fetzer's weekly time book, 1908-1909, for work on a Manassas school building; an unidentified photo of a woman and child; miscellaneous catalogs and advertisements; and various arrival notices, freight bills, and cashier's memoranda from the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company, 1928-1929.
  - Plan, 17 January 1925 (Oversize 8, Oversize 9)
    Details of Walks contracted for on January 17, 1925, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia - Charles F. Gillette, Landscape Architect. Plan No. 180-24